Lasitha Nipun

Front-End Developer

Villa, S- 35, Al Samha, Abu Dhabi. 0522543307 lasithadilshan851@gmail.com



ABOUT ME

I'm Lasitha Nipun and 29 years old. With 6 years of experience in IT with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology industry. Area of expertise includes Web design, Development and Graphic Design. I'm educated in Sri Lanka with excellent communication skills, ability to work under pressure, skills for liaising with clients, and attention to details.

PORTFOLIO

https://lasitha851.github.io/profile/



EXPERIENCE

Seeduwa Software Development Solution Sub Branch of Globe Internet limited Malawi Seeduwa, Sri Lanka.

Front-End Developer & Graphic Designer

JAN 2018 TO JUNE 2022

- Maintain company websites, softwares and apps front end.
- Maintain seven WordPress based websites.
- Develop UI mockups and prototypes that clearly illustrate how sites function and look like.
- Identify and troubleshoot UX problems for websites and mobile apps.
- Determining the structure and design of the web pages uses multiple front- end languages and libraries (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap & React.js).
- Design and develop the corporate websites ensuring strong functionality and optimization.
- Manage and update website contents using CMS like Wordpress, Joomla, Drupal, & Magento.
- Play a team member as the company outsources projects.
- Working with version control systems such as GIT.
- Manage social media marketing & advertisements (Facebook & Google).
- Create graphic design, Logos, Flyers, and posters using Photoshop, Illustrator, Coreldraw, and Indesign.

IDM Nations Campus (Pvt) Ltd - Junior Lecturer

Gampaha, Sri Lanka.

MAR 2017 TO DEC 2020

 Work as Visiting Lecturer Graphic Design, Web Design & Development, and Android Development

Lanka Shipping & Logistics (Pvt) Ltd - Web Developer as freelancer

Colombo 03, Sri Lanka.

FEB 2021 TO APRIL 2022

- Maintain six WordPress based websites.
- Proper management of the Cpanel.
- Maintain Testing website domains / live domains separately.
- Checking website forms for vulnerability.
- Website & DB backups.
- Anti Scan and save the logs.
- SSL management.

General Information Systems (Pvt) Ltd - Junior Web Developer

Colombo 10, Sri Lanka.

MAR 2015 TO MAR 2017

- Create HTML/CSS websites from a design with responsive layouts
- Designed websites with WordPress
- Appreciation for design aesthetics
- Ability to use Javascript for interactive page elements
- Developed backend use php and MYSQL

EDUCATION

Buckinghamshire New University - B.Sc in Computing

JAN 2020 TO 2021

Edhat International - HND in Computing and Systems Development

JAN 2018 TO 2020

Diploma in Web Design and Development - Lalith Athulathmudali Vocational Training Center (LAVTC)

2015

Diploma in Java Programming - LAVTC

2016

- Java SE
- Java EE

Advance Certificate in Computerized Non-Linear Video Editing with Digital 3D Animation -

LAVTC

- 2016
 - 3D Max
 - Adobe After Effects
 - Adobe Premiere
 - Poser

Certificate in Graphic Designing- Wijaya Graphics

2016

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe PageMaker
- Adobe InDesign

Certificate in Electronic Engineering Technology - LAVTC

2016

- Basic Principles of Electronics
- Digital Electronics
- PCB Designing Using ORCAD

Certificate in Microcontroller Circuit Designing - LAVTC

2016

- PIC Microcontroller
- Arduino

Certificate in English

2010

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Scouting

2005 to present

- President Scout (6358) in 2012
- Participated in National And International Event

Dancing

2007 To 2014

Participated in National Events

Sports

2007 To 2014

Participated in National Events

PERSONAL DETAILS

Full Name - Hewa Ulawaduge Lasitha Nipun Dilshan

Date of Birth - 18-03-1993

Gender - Male
Civil Status - Married
Nationality - Sri Lankan

N.I.C. No - 199307800642

Passport No - N9174031

School Attended - Galahitiyawa Central College, Ganemulla.

I hereby certify that the above particulars furnished by me are true and accurate according to the best of my knowledge.

lasitha

Lasitha Nipun.